<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://blog.abishekn.com.np/blog</id>
    <title>Abi's Blog Blog</title>
    <updated>2025-04-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://blog.abishekn.com.np/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Abi's Blog Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://blog.abishekn.com.np/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>Copyright © 2025 Abishek Neupane</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everyday Reflections: Life's Unexpected Moments]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.abishekn.com.np/blog/everyday-reflections</id>
        <link href="https://blog.abishekn.com.np/blog/everyday-reflections"/>
        <updated>2025-04-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Personal reflections on everyday struggles in Nepal from the lens of a non-political observer.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone, I just want to share some random thoughts today. Here in Nepal, people who aren’t interested in politicians, parties, or all that drama seem to suffer the most. I’ve had so many experiences—some made me feel terrible, others were good. Everything that’s happened to me, I always thought it’d leave a positive mark, teaching me lessons along the way.</p>
<p>There’s a lot swirling in my head right now. Honestly, people who went abroad right after +2 wouldn’t get what I’m talking about. I think those who left after their bachelor’s might understand more—they’ve probably seen more than I have.</p>
<p>I see quarrels everywhere here. Me, I’ve never been the type to fight or argue. Even when I’m not wrong, I end up saying sorry just to keep the peace. Sometimes, being too polite or asking simple questions makes you feel bad. Take today, for example—I was in Kathmandu for WordCamp 2025. I stopped at a local cafe and ordered a cup of tea. I didn’t have small change, so I handed the guy a 500-rupee note. He said he didn’t have change, which was fine—I get it, maybe I was the first customer of the day. So I asked if there was a QR code to pay digitally. He said no, and I was shocked. I went to a nearby shop, bought something I didn’t even need just to break the 500, and came back to pay. Then he goes, “Why should I get a QR code for this? If it was something like rice or a big meal, I’d understand.” Bro, who comes to your shop at 6 a.m. to eat a heavy meal? So yeah, that’s just one little thing from today.</p>
<p>I’ve been through a lot and forgotten even more. Public transport here? Don’t get me started. I’ve had so many bad experiences. Whenever I travel to Kathmandu, back to Chitwan, or anywhere else, it’s always a mess. I ask for a specific seat when I buy my ticket, and they tell me it’s full, shoving me to the back. Later, I find out it wasn’t full—they just wanted to pack the back seats first. The fares? I’ve been cheated so many times. They charge whatever they feel like. Once, they owed me 300 rupees in change—it was even written on the ticket—but they argued with me and refused to pay. During festivals, not even on the main day of Dashain, but toward the end, they double the fare. Where do I complain? How do I fix this? I just end up letting it go.</p>
<p>And education? It’s a disaster. I study at Tribhuvan University (TU), Institute of Science and Technology. I’ve switched between two government colleges. I’m not into politics or parties—you probably know how things work there if you’re not involved. The education system is a total waste, at least from my perspective. TU and its government colleges feel like a cheap certificate factory. You’re on your own—your browser tabs are your real teachers. I’m not blaming the teachers; it’s the system. Getting anything done takes forever—long processes for even the smallest service.</p>
<p>I’m exhausted, honestly. Still, I’m hoping for the best.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Abishek Neupane</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/virtualabishek</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="betryed" term="betryed"/>
        <category label="Non Technical" term="Non Technical"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Linux Journey and the Power of WSL]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.abishekn.com.np/blog/linux-and-wsl-journeys</id>
        <link href="https://blog.abishekn.com.np/blog/linux-and-wsl-journeys"/>
        <updated>2025-04-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring Linux, distro-hopping, and how WSL changed my development workflow.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="introduction">Introduction<a href="https://blog.abishekn.com.np/blog/linux-and-wsl-journeys#introduction" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Introduction" title="Direct link to Introduction">​</a></h2>
<p>If you’ve ever wondered about dipping your toes into Linux without leaving the comfort of Windows, you’re in good company. I’m not experienced one but someone who’s explored operating systems with curiosity and a bit of trial-and-error.
In this post, I’ll walk you through my Linux journey, from my early experiments to finding Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL). It’s been quite a ride, and I hope sharing it sparks something for you.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="my-story-with-linux-and-wsl">My Story with Linux and WSL<a href="https://blog.abishekn.com.np/blog/linux-and-wsl-journeys#my-story-with-linux-and-wsl" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to My Story with Linux and WSL" title="Direct link to My Story with Linux and WSL">​</a></h2>
<p>For anyone new to the term, <strong>Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL)</strong> is a feature that lets you run a Linux environment right on your Windows machine. No need for a separate virtual machine or dual-boot setup—it’s a seamless way to blend the best of both worlds, especially for developers.</p>
<p>My Linux adventure kicked off years ago, thanks to my brother <strong>Acyut Dai</strong>, who first showed me the ropes. I was hooked right away, even if I didn’t fully grasp the technical side back then. One memory stands out: I went to a shop to buy a laptop and asked for <strong>Linux Mint</strong> instead of Windows. The salesperson was caught off guard—probably not a request he got every day. That was my launchpad into the Linux world.</p>
<p>With <strong>Linux Mint</strong> on my laptop, I dove in, exploring its features for hours. Truth be told, I didn’t have a strong grip on the basics. Over time, I bounced between <strong>12 to 15 different Linux distributions</strong>, chasing the next shiny thing without really mastering any of them. Looking back, I was more caught up in the excitement than in laying a solid groundwork.</p>
<p>Fast forward a bit, and I got access to Windows developer features, which led me to <strong>WSL</strong>. It was a total game-changer. Suddenly, I felt more productive, blending Linux tools into my Windows routine effortlessly. I think Windows saw how much developers were leaning toward Linux and built WSL to meet that need. It’s pretty powerful—think installing packages with a quick <code>sudo apt install</code> instead of wrestling with Windows-specific headaches.</p>
<p>I’ve never fully clicked with Windows’ own command-line tools, though that’s probably on me for not digging deeper. Windows is great for tons of people; WSL just smooths out certain tasks for me.</p>
<p>WSL has made a huge impact for developers globally, though it’s not a must-have for everyone—it’s all about what works for you. As a newbie blogger, I’m just here to share my take. <strong>Here’s what I’ve loved about WSL:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Command-Line Power</strong>: It rekindled my appreciation for the command line—super efficient and flexible.</li>
<li><strong>Easy Setup</strong>: Installing languages and packages is a breeze, cutting down on setup time.</li>
<li><strong>Storage Smarts</strong>: From what I’ve seen, WSL handles storage for code and modules pretty efficiently compared to a full Linux setup (though your mileage might vary).</li>
</ul>
<p>There’s tons more to dig into, and I’d love to hear what you think about WSL if you’ve tried it!</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://blog.abishekn.com.np/blog/linux-and-wsl-journeys#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Looking back, WSL has become a key part of my development toolkit. It ties Windows and Linux together, letting me tap into both without the chaos of my distro-hopping phase. My Linux days taught me to <strong>stay focused while learning</strong>, and WSL keeps me grounded.</p>
<p>If you haven’t checked it out yet, <strong>give it a whirl!</strong> Already a user? I’d love your thoughts. Thanks for reading my first post—more to come!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Abishek Neupane</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/virtualabishek</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Technical" term="Technical"/>
        <category label="Linux" term="Linux"/>
        <category label="WSL" term="WSL"/>
        <category label="Windows" term="Windows"/>
        <category label="Development" term="Development"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Too Much Philosophy, Not Enough Presence]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.abishekn.com.np/blog/too-much-philosophy</id>
        <link href="https://blog.abishekn.com.np/blog/too-much-philosophy"/>
        <updated>2025-04-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A reflection on the balance between thinking and truly living.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, I stumbled across a post on X that really hit me.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="zxx" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/28bsnyYSZK">pic.twitter.com/28bsnyYSZK</a></p><p>— ★ (@thematrixwizard)<!-- --> </p><a href="https://twitter.com/thematrixwizard/status/1898988630967800312?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"><p>March 10, 2025</p></a></blockquote>
<!-- -->
<p>The caption was simple: <strong>"Too much philosophy, not enough presence."</strong> And honestly, it felt so true. We spend so much of our lives chasing positivity—trying to do good, be good, and hope only the best comes our way. But life doesn’t always play along, does it?</p>
<p>A while back, I wrote something that ties into this. It went like this:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"These days, the internet is full of inspirational sayings, movies, and postings. However, what matters most is how much you use them in your life, regardless of how much you read or watch. Nothing is permanent, not even your beliefs, driving forces, or favorite quotations. Maybe you only remember them when you're in a good mood. When you're feeling down or unhappy, I'm sure you lose sight of your motivation."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>You can read more of my ramblings here: <a href="https://abishekn.com.np/perspective" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">abishekn.com.np/perspective</a>.</p>
<p>Here’s the thing: all this hustling we do—working hard for a nice house, a fancy car, or to get better at something—it’s really about <strong>presence</strong>. People always say, <em>“Don’t dwell on the past, it’ll hurt you.”</em> Fair enough. But I’d argue looking too far into the future can mess up your <strong>now</strong> just as much. Every second you spend distracted or lost? It’s gone forever. You don’t get it back.</p>
<p>So, what I’m getting at is this: <strong>focus on the moment</strong>. Enjoy the process. I’m convinced that’s where real joy and happiness hide. Think about it—you forget where you left your keys, you miss an important moment because you’re zoned out, or you finally get something you’ve always wanted and feel that rush of pride. But do you remember how hard you worked for it? Probably not. Success has a way of wiping the slate clean. Then, boom, new desires pop up, and the cycle starts again.</p>
<p>That’s life, right? An endless loop of wanting, chasing, and forgetting. We all know this deep down—it’s nothing groundbreaking. But living it? Actually <strong>staying present</strong>? That’s the tricky part.</p>
<p>I’ll be real with you—I’m not even sure where I’m going with this. It’s just a stream of thoughts, typed out for fun. Hope you enjoyed it, though! Thanks for reading, and catch you in the next one.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Abishek Neupane</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/virtualabishek</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Philosophy" term="Philosophy"/>
        <category label="Non Technical" term="Non Technical"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.abishekn.com.np/blog/first-blog</id>
        <link href="https://blog.abishekn.com.np/blog/first-blog"/>
        <updated>2024-04-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! This is my first blog post.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello! This is my first blog post.</p>
<p>More content goes here...</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Abishek Neupane</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/virtualabishek</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Technical" term="Technical"/>
    </entry>
</feed>